as an e-commerce seller have you ever
wondered the best way to manage your
inventory while still using a 3pl hi I'm
Stacy with Ledger gurus and today I'm
going to explain to you why you need an
inventory management system even if you
are using a 3pl for fulfillment when I
speak with clients I often hear people
tell me that they don't need an
inventory management system because
they're using a
3pl well today I want to clear up that
misconception if you're using a 3pl then
you already know that it manages all
your warehouse and fulfillment processes
when an order comes in it's sent through
to the 3pl and somebody at the 3pl picks
packs and chips the order you might even
get a monthly or quarterly report from
the 3pl telling you what's been
fulfilled and possibly what's left on
the Shelf the 3pl is also likely using
some kind of a shipping tool what you're
missing with the 3pl is everything on
the operational and accounting side of
your inventory your 3pl doesn't manage
your available inventory across multiple
selling channels any kind of forecasting
including when you need to send more
inventory to the 3pl or to Amazon
purchasing inventory and most
importantly your cost of goods sold a
good Inventory management system will
keep track of where your inventory is at
any moment is it in transit to the
warehouse is it in transit to the
customer is it sitting on a shelf it
also manages your purchasing process
along with forecasting a good IMS will
look at historical sales and leadtime
requirements in order to generate
purchase orders so you never run out of
inventory most importantly an IMS
automates everything around cost of
goods sold knowing your profitability is
critical to the success of your
e-commerce business if you are an
e-commerce seller then it's time to
consider an inventory management system
even if you are using a 3pl for
fulfillment if you would like help
choosing an inventory management system
for your business please contact us
through the link below if this video was
helpful like it leave a question in the
comments and subscribe to our channel
for more helpful e-commerce accounting
tips